

Paul Ursby

SW developer in Automation & looking for challenges within AI & ML

Profile

I am a highly motivated and social person with an efficient, positive, and highquality mindset. I am seeking new challenges in my career, particularly in the fields of AI and ML (Machine Learning), where I continuously invest significant effort in upskilling. This field truly fascinates me, and I would love to contribute to its future progress.

I possess over 20 years of experience, primarily in the Testing and Development domains within the Telecom industry. My work has ranged from deep technical level, crafting Test strategies up to Business Unit level, to Test leading and coordinating. I believe that my combined expertise in Technology, Strategies, and Ways of Working is one of my strengths.

Throughout my career, I have gained experience in most stages of a product's life cycle, including requirements gathering, system design, development, testing, customer delivery, and support. Currently, I am a Software Developer in a cloudnative environment, focusing on Kubernetes, Python, and CI/CD pipelines.

My recent achievements include:

- Developing an Ericsson Software Delivery Pipeline product that enables automated deployment of cloud-native telecom applications, utilizing technologies such as Kubernetes, GitLab, Spinnaker, Jenkins and Jira.
- In a short-term role I worked in an Applied Machine Learning Research group, where I prototyped and applied Machine Learning to Telecom applications.
- Due to my strong interest in Machine Learning, I have dedicated significant effort to upskilling. I have completed several courses, both external and internal to Ericsson, as detailed on my LinkedIn profile.

I am often entrusted by my managers with complex tasks and consistently receive positive feedback, such as "If you are given a task, one can trust that it will be completed independently, with high quality and on time", "You think outside the box" and "You drive tasks efficiently".

I am not afraid to take on responsibilities outside my usual domain, and I consider myself an effective team player and a sociable individual. I have led teams in both technical and strategic/process-related areas. I have international experience, having undertaken both long and short-term

assignments both within Ericsson and with customers abroad.

Employment History

Software Developer in Automation - Ericsson AB (PDU PC), Gothenburg, Sweden

2020 - Present

• Responsible for developing a Software Delivery Pipeline that continuously and with high automation, deploys or upgrades the software of several Packet Core products in customer networks.

Personal Information

Gothenburg, Sweden +46702801800 paulursby@hotmail.com



Professional skills

Python programming

Machine Learning, including LLMs

Data Science stacks like Scikit, Panda, NumPy and Seaborn

Cloud technologies like Kubernetes, GitLab, Spinnaker and Jenkins

Agile and DevOps methodologies and tools

Testing methodologies and strategies

Ericsson Packet Core products

Languages

Swedish

Native

Enalish

Fluent

German

Conversational

Courses completed recently

- Generative AI for SW Development Specialization
- · Generative AI with LLM
- Applied Data Science Camp -Graduate 2023
- Mathematics for ML and DS Specialization
- Kubernetes and Cloud Native **Essentials**
- Introduction to GitOps

Employment History

Software Developer in Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) - Ericsson AB (PDU PC), Gothenburg, Sweden

2022 - 2022

As part of a team, I performed AI and ML-related system studies and prototyping within the Packet Core area, which includes experimental data handling and ML model tuning activities, as well as evaluating the results.

Strategic I&V Technical Test Coordinator - Ericsson AB (PDU PC), Gothenburg, Sweden

2013 - 2018

Main responsible and driver of strategic testing aspects in the following contexts:

- End-to-end testing of Packet Core products at the department level.
- All types of testing of Packet Core products in a newly emerging cloud and 5G environment at the Product Development Unit level.
- Testing of Ericsson products in a cloud environment at Business Unit level.

I&V Technical Test Coordinator - Ericsson AB (PDU PC), Gothenburg, Sweden

2009 - 2013

- Main driver of crafting test strategies, plans, and processes at various organizational levels.
- Served as a Technical Test Coordinator for end-to-end I&V of Packet Core products, working with 2G, 3G, and 4G networks.

Senior I&V / Test Engineer - Ericsson AB (PDU PC), Gothenburg, Sweden

2001 - 2009

- Acted as a senior troubleshooter within the Test area and verified several nodes in a mobile Packet Core network and.
- Conducted testing at both functional and system levels and verified nodes within a complete mobile network.

Support and I&V Engineer - LM Ericsson Ltd, Dublin, Ireland

1999 - 2001

- Responsibilities included support to external customers and verification of IN services from the local development centre.
- Worked with Intelligent Network (IN) services, such as PrePaid and VPN, in both mobile and fixed network.

System Designer, Test-, Integrator- and Support Engineer - Ericsson Software Technology AB, Karlskrona, Sweden

1995 - 1999

- Verified IN services at both functional and system levels.
- Installed and integrated IN services at customer sites and provided customer support from home office.
- Engaged in system design for IN services.

Education

2019: Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning

Engaged in self-study, primarily through various online courses from platforms such as Coursera, Google, and edX. For more detailed information, see my LinkedIn profile.

2019: **National Economy**, Basic Course Lund University

1994 - 1995: Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering –

Emphasis on Telecommunications Karlskrona/Ronneby University College

1992: **Business Economics**, Basic Course Gothenburg School of Business, Economics, and Law

1989 - 1991: University
Certificate in Electrical
Engineering, Telecommunications
Linnaeus University in Växjö

References

References are available upon request.